To change everything, she gave everything.
The Fire Inside is a drama, history film directed by Rachel Morrison.
Claressa Shields, a high school junior from Flint, Michigan, aided by her tough-love coach, Jason Crutchfield,
pushes past all limitations to become the first American woman to win an Olympic gold medal in boxing.
But even at the pinnacle of success, Claressa has to reckon with the fact that not
all dreams are created equal, and the real fight has only just begun.
Claressa 'T-Rex' Shields, played by Ryan Destiny.
Jason Crutchfield, played by Brian Tyree Henry.
Jackie Shields, played by Oluniké Adeliyi.
Young Claressa (Running), played by Kylee D. Allen.
USA Team Officer, played by Emmanuel Igboke.
Coach Parker, played by Lanette Ware.
The Fire Inside is a 2024 American biographical sports film by
Rachel Morrison in her feature directorial debut.
The film is about the early boxing career of Claressa "T-Rex" Shields, a fighter from
Flint, Michigan, including her competing at the 2012 Summer Olympics.
Ryan Destiny stars as Shields, alongside Brian Tyree Henry and Adam Clark.
Originally titled Flint Strong during development, The Fire Inside premiered in the Special Presentations section of the Toronto International Film Festival on September 7, 2024, and was
released in the United States by Amazon MGM Studios on December 25, 2024 to positive reviews but was a box office bomb, grossing only $8.1 million on a $12 million budget.
The film explores themes of child abuse, biography, based on
true story, teenage girl, flint michigan.
The tone is emotional.